OLUWATOSIN TOLASE-AKINTOLA

Kitchener, Ontario, N2R 0K4

+1 437-988-0711 ~ <u>oluwatosintolase@gmail.com</u>

Dedicated Business Systems Analyst, with extensive experience in analyzing business needs, process re-engineering, and system implementation using Agile, Waterfall and Hybrid methodologies. Excellent leadership skills with proficiency in developing relationships, building consensus, and leading positive organizational change.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- Agile, Scrum
- Continuous improvement, LEAN, TPM
- Database Management
- Lean Six Sigma Techniques
- Negotiation

- MS Office (Project, Excel, PPT, Word)
- Salesforce, MS Dynamics
- Business Process Re-engineering
- Business Stakeholder Management
- Oracle, Jira, Visio
- Vendor Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Business Analyst, Divine Care Conglomerate

07/2021 - 09/2022

- Document Business Requirements, Use Cases, Software Requirement Specifications and Functional specifications for the Brick's application releases
- Prepare process and data models; using Visio to create workflow, Use Case and other BPMN Language (BPMN 2.0) based diagrams for a payment Reporting software
- Prepare and document test plan documents in collaboration with QA team for User Acceptance
 Testing (UAT), System Integration Testing (SIT), generating test cases from business use cases and
 documented test script
- Facilitate Joint Application Design (JAD) sessions to elicit requirements through brainstorming for new and enhanced system development efforts in online banking and credit underwriting solutions
- Lead walkthroughs, validation and discovery sessions with key stakeholders when eliciting process components in business transformation and improvement projects
- Liaise with business users, subject matter experts, and development team to highlight opportunities for process improvements and business process automation for client's and internal users
- Define data elements on database tables as they will be extracted from source systems (Microsoft NAV), and other Proprietary systems) to destination target.
- Develop and maintain applications using SQL languages including creating and tuning
 high-performance queries during ETL projects from Source data centers to destination data warehouse
- Strong understanding of the entire system architecture from a Data base perspective and working on data models to support the project
- Analyze various business processes and identified new opportunities, business processes and strategies for more efficient and optimized processes.
- Create an FDD and captured transformation rules to identify database tables that will be impacted during data migration from source to destination/target systems
- Conduct business analysis requirements gathering and documentation, and validation testing
- Lead analysis of business process workflow and alternative solutions considering benefits, risks and costs.

- Analyze and summarize data used in models, analysis and tracking against forecast and business objectives
- Document procedural documents and ensued they were consistent with policy and structural changes
- Organize and coordinate project approval processes for various levels of the governance structure
- Identify and document business environment, functional and non-functional requirements

Business Analysis Specialist Telemed MD

04/2021 - 06/2021

- Participated and conducted walkthroughs for business requirements, design specification documents, and approval of functional test plans for the end-to-end automation
- Triaged and resolved Incident tickets and actioned request tickets remotely and in-person
- Supported vulnerability testing and, adding security patches to computers on the network
- Reviewed existing business processes and workflows to identify opportunities for improvement including modifying, streamlining, and automating manual processes
- Conducted process analysis, gap analysis and investigation of existing functionalities of various business processing and making recommendations to executive management accordingly
- Conducted business analysis requirements gathering and documentation, and validation testing
- Led analysis of business process workflow and alternative solutions considering benefits, risks and costs.
- Analyzed and summarized data used in models, analysis and tracking against forecast and business objectives
- Documented procedural documents and ensued they were consistent with policy and structural changes
- organized and coordinated project approval processes for various levels of the governance structure
- Identifying, analyzing and documenting business environment, functional and non-functional requirements
- Liaised and coordinated with other teams including the client, the business and project management
- Facilitated sessions with project team members and business stakeholders daily to determine project vision and created vendor service level agreements

Business Analyst- Nubian, Lagos, Nigeria

07/2012 - 01/ 2020

- Conducted business analysis requirements gathering and documentation, and validation testing
- Led analysis of business process workflow and alternative solutions considering benefits, risks and costs.
- Analyzed and summarized data used in models, analysis and tracking against forecast and business objectives
- Documented procedural documents and ensued they were consistent with policy and structural changes
- organized and coordinated project approval processes for various levels of the governance structure
- Identifying, analyzing and documenting business environment, functional and non-functional requirements
- Facilitated sessions with project team members and business stakeholders daily to determine project vision and created vendor service level agreements.
- Created test cases for UAT testing with business users and supported QA team during QA testing
- Acted as a liaison between the business and IT for technical/sales projects; meeting with business partners to determine current and future needs.

- Facilitated information gathering sessions with business and/or technology partners (requirements gathering, cost benefit analysis, etc.)
- Led the project team members to meet project objectives through successful execution against project scope, schedule, and cost
- Identified and led the resolution of project issues; devised effective ways of reaching project objectives in the most cost/time-effective manner while considering unique business conditions

EDUCATION	
Business and Digital Marketing Specialist, Trios College	2021
Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomosho, Nigeria	2009